# NICHOLAS KIPNGENO

# **Profile Summary**

I am a degree student in Software Engineering from KCA university graduating in December 2023.I have a knack for software development and system maintenance. I am driven by results and a passion for attaining and surpassing goals set out by me and organizations. I seek to

Grow and further develop my skills in software development, management, using my experiences, complemented by knowledge, to be a dependable and organized team player with the ability to communicate effectively and efficiently.

## Areas of Expertise

- Team Player/building
- React JS
- SQL Databases
- R Programming
- JavaScript
- Firebase
- Data Cleaning
- Data Visualization
- Power BI
- Git
- Node JS
- Material UI

-

## Personal Details:

Gender: Male Age: 22Years Nationality: Kenyan Native Languages: English, Kiswahili

## Main Interests:

- Coding
- Entrepreneurship
  - Travelling
  - Cooking
  - Photography
  - Social media

# Contact Information:

Email: nicholaskipngeno622@gmail.com Cell Phone: +254725147169

## Work Experience

# UPWORK FREELANCER UPWORK MARCH 2022 TO FEBURUARY 2023

Participated in pre-project analysis and technical assessments to validate creation of user-friendly interface.

Built reusable code to utilize for other projects and to minimize costs.

Researched new programming languages, frameworks and technologies to stay abreast with latest trend.

Designed layout and graphics to enhance aesthetics and appearance of website. Liaised with team to develop content and choose applicable solutions to create and maintain website.

Responded to queries on private messages or comments to address issues and resolve complaints.

Tested links to identify and rectify discrepancies, determine speed and gauge traffic

Used JAVA, HTML or XML to structure web pages and provide smooth navigation of internet.

Wrote and created codes and programs to infuse power for databases and servers. Troubleshot website on different browsers to determine quality.

## **AUCTIONEERING INTERN**

AUCKLAND AGENCIES JULY 2022 TO OCTOBER 2022

.

- -created and updated databases of items to be auctioned
- implemented payment plans for clients buying auctioned goods.
- Assisted specialists and associates in cataloging lots for upcoming auctions
- Assisted in conducting and compiling research on key clients and industries
- Managed upkeep of department databases and trackers
- Assisted and facilitated staff on individual projects as necessary

## **Education**

## **DEGREE IN SOFTWARE ENGINEERING**

KCA UNIVERSITY -

Attended from 2019 – 2022 (AWAITING GRADUATION)

## PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATE IN CISCO COMPUTER NETWORKING

KCA UNIVERSITY

Attended from JANUARY 2021 – MARCH 2021 (CERTIFICATES ATTAINED)

#### GOOGLE DATA ANALYTICS CERTIFICATE

#### COURSERA

Attended from JULY 2022- DECEMBER 2022(CERTIFICATION ATTAINED)

## References

## 1. JOHN KURIA

DEAN OF STUDENTS- KCA UNIVERSITY

TEL: 0722-474-955

2. REHEMA KIRUI

SENIOR AUCTIONEER

AUCKLAND AGENCIES

TEL: 0718-302-007

#### LINKEDIN PROFILE

https://www.linkedin.com/in/nicholas-kipngeno

## **GITHUB**

https://github.com/Nickkirui/